A Guide to the Papers of George Stevenson Kemp
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Geoge Stevenson Kemp Papers 1965-1984
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M240
7.5 linear feet
George Stevenson Kemp
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated to the Special Collections and Archives Department by Mrs. Wilana Kemp in September 1987. All rights were transferred to Virginia Commonwealth University by Deed of Gift 24 September 1987. Accession Number: 87-MAY-26
Biographical/Historical Information
George Stevenson (Steve) Kemp, Jr. (1916-1986), a native of Richmond, attended public elementary schools, McGuire's School and Washington and Lee University. He went to work in the financial district of Richmond in 1936. In 1939 he joined the brokerage firm of Abbott, Proctor & Paine (later merging to become Paine Webber Inc.) and became a general partner in 1947. Drafted into the Army in 1942, Kemp went to Air Corps officer candidate school and was discharge a captain in 1946. The member of several financial organizations, Kemp was encouraged to run for Richmond City Council in the early 1970s but did not. After his retirement in 1976, Kemp ran for City Couuncil representing the 1st District in 1978, and was re-elected in 1980 and 1982. Kemp did not seek re-election in 1984 but took up the retirement activities he had deferred. Mr. Kemp died 24 June 1986.
Scope and Content Information
The collection includes Mr. Kemp's working papers, correspondence, files and reports relating to the city of Richmond (1961-1986). The bulk of the materials focus on the years Mr. Kemp was active in the Richmond City Council (1980-1984).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Alternate G (Box-folder 1:1)
- Black Agenda 1980 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Botanical Garden 1983-1984 (Box-folder 1:3)
- CENSUS 1980 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Cheagle 1983 (Box-folder 1:5)
- City Attorney Hefty 1983 (Box-folder 1:6)
- City Council 1978 (Box-folder 1:7)
- City of Richmond 1985-1986 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Claudette McDaniel and Police Morale 1978-1980 1 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Claudette McDaniel and Police Morale 1978-1980 2 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Clean City Commission/'Spring Clean Richmond Week' 1979 (Box-folder 2:3)
- Collective Bargaining 1978-1983 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Correspondence Completed A-K 1978-1983 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Correspondence Completed L-Z 1978-1980 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Council Certification (Box-folder 3:2)
- Council Member Resumes (Box-folder 3:3)
- Deese, Manuel--City Manger Correspondence (Box-folder 3:4)
- Election 1978 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Election 1978 Materials (Box-folder 3:6)
- Election 1980 Campaign (Box-folder 3:7)
- Election 1982 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Energy Committee 1979-1982 (Box-folder 3:9)
- Expense Account Committee 1982-1983 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Expenses in Court 1983 (Box-folder 3:11)
- Federated Arts Council (Box-folder 3:12)
- Finance 1983 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Flood Wall 1978-1982 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Food Bank 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Fourteenth Annual Convention of the National Federation of Financial Analysts Societies (Box-folder 4:4)
- Freeman Fisher Gosden Day 1981 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Goldman--Education Issues 1981-1983 (Box-folder 4:6)
- H.R. Ordinance 1983 (Box-folder 4:7)
- H.R. Ordinance 1977-1982 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Huguenot Bridge and Connector 1978-1984 1 (Box-folder 4:9)
- Huguenot Bridge and Connector 1978-1984 2 (Box-folder 5:1)
- Industrial Development Authority 1983-1984 (Box-folder 5:2)
- Interstate 295 1979-1983 (Box-folder 5:3)
- Invoices 1980 (Box-folder 5:4)
- Jurisdictions-RCH 1978-1979 (Box-folder 6:1)
- Keith-Three Chopt Project 1982-1983 Federated Arts Council (Box-folder 6:2)
- King, Martin Luther (Box-folder 6:3)
- Legal 1978-1983 (Box-folder 6:4)
- Leidinger Affair 1978 Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 6:5)
- Leidinger Affair 1978 Correspondence (Box-folder 6:6)
- Leidinger-Marsh 1978 (Box-folder 6:7)
- Leigh Street Extension 1980-1983 (Box-folder 6:8)
- Lewis Ginter Botanical Garden (Box-folder 6:9)
- Lockgreen 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7:1)
  See also Windsor Farms
- Mackenzie-- Richmond News Leader 1980 (Box-folder 7:2)
- Marsh 1979-1981 (Box-folder 7:3)
- Marsh 1980-1982 Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 7:4)
- Mattox 1980-1981 (Box-folder 7:5)
- Maymont Foundation 1979, 1981 (Box-folder 7:6)
- Mays Valentine JPA/WRC (Box-folder 7:7)
- Miscellaneous (Box-folder 7:8)
- Miscellaneous--Marsh and City Council (Box-folder 8:1)
- Miscellaneous Data--Lockgreen/Windsor Farms 1985 (Box-folder 8:2)
- Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles 1980-1982 (Box-folder 8:3)
- Municipal League Meeting UVA 1978 (Box-folder 8:4)
- Non-Departmental 1981-1982 (Box-folder 8:5)
- Old City Hall 1978-1981 (Box-folder 8:6)
- On the Extension of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (Box-folder 8:7)
- Parking Meters-Downtown 1981 (Box-folder 8:8)
- Parham-Chippenham Connector 1984 (Box-folder 8:9)
- Parham-Chippenham Connector 1983-1984 (Box-folder 8:10)
- Parham-Chippenham Connector 1983-1984 (Box-folder 9:1)
- Police Morale 1975-1980 (Box-folder 9:2)
- Police Morale Study Newspaper Clippings 1980 (Box-folder 9:3)
- Precious Metals 1981 (Box-folder 9:4)
- Procedures Information 1964, 1978 (Box-folder 9:5)
- Protection Against Crime Bulletins (Box-folder 9:6)
- R--Rating of Council (Box-folder 9:7)
- Race Relations Richmond 1980-1984 (Box-folder 9:8)
- RCH Clippings--Jurisdictions (Box-folder 9:9)
- Real Estate Assessment (Box-folder 9:10)
- Redistricting City and Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 10:1)
- Redistricting City 1979 (Box-folder 10:2)
- Redistricting Clippings (Box-folder 10:3)
- Redistricting Correspondence 1981-1982 (Box-folder 10:4)
- Redistricting Letter Soliciting for the Department of Justice 1981 (Box-folder 10:5)
- Redistricting Letter 1981 (Box-folder 11:1)
- Referendum RITA "£"2 (Box-folder 11.2)
- Report of the Citizens Crime Committee June 1977 (Box-folder 11:3)
- Retreat 1981-1982 (Box-folder 11:4)
- Richmond City Code 1979-1982 (Box-folder 11:5)
- Richmond Renaissance 1985-1986 (Box-folder 11:6)
- Richmond Renaissance--Minutes (Box-folder 12:1)
- RITA Expenses 1980-1981 (Box-folder 12:2)
- River Road--Huguenot 1980-1984 (Box-folder 12:3)
- Sauer's Garden 1978-1981 (Box-folder 12:4)
- School Board 1978-1983 (Box-folder 12:5)
- Selection Committee--City Manager (Box-folder 13:1)
- Speeches/Remarks 1978-1981 (Box-folder 13:2)
- Stony Point Development 1982-1984 (Box-folder 13:3)
- Summary of Issues--Divestiture South Africa 1985 (Box-folder 13:4)
- Tangible Personal Property 1979-1981 (Box-folder 13:5)
- Teams for Progress 1978-1982 (Box-folder 13:6)
- Three Chopt Project (Box-folder 13:7)
  See also Keith Three Chopt Project
- Trash--Landfills Recycling 1979 (Box-folder 13:8)
- Virginia Municipal League 1983 (Box-folder 14:1)
- Voting Rights (Box-folder 14:2)
  See On extension of Voting Rights Act
- West--Mayor of Richmond 1982-1983 (Box-folder 14:3)
- West Cary Street Neighborhood Club 1980-1981 (Box-folder 14:4)
- Williams, Geline 1984 (Box-folder 14:5)
- Windfall Profits Tax 1978-1980 (Box-folder 14:6)
- Windsor Farms/Lockgreen 1961, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 14:7)
- 1984-1986 Proposed General Fund (Box-folder 14:8)
- Miscellaneous Booklets
  Assessing Real Estate
  Census 1980
  Charter of Richmond Virginia
  City of Richmond Telephone Directory
  Confederate Military Hospitals in Richmond
  Election Summary Totals 1977-1978
  Huguenot and River Roads Stage Report
  Potential Corporate Contributors 1979-1980
  Richmond Information